Everyone else is able to do it, so why am I the only one that can't?
大家都做得到的事情 為什麼只有我做不到呢？
I've been doing a fairly good job getting by
成人出社會之後
as a working adult.
我的工作一帆風順
But when it comes to sex…
但唯有性經驗…
I want to also be someone that has experienced sex.
我也想變成有性經驗的人
Thanks for yesterday. Here's the picture!
昨天辛苦了，這是照片
In my 32 years, I've never experienced having sex,
32年來，從來沒有過性經驗的我
but the chance to finally came around yesterday.
昨天終於有機會了
I'm sorry I'm late.
不好意思，我遲到了
-Oh! -Saeki, you're late!
-喔！ -佐伯，你太慢了啦！
Long time no see, Kosaka.
香坂，好久不見了
Saeki.
佐伯
If you don't mind…
你願意的話…
Could you do it with me?
能和我做嗎？
Can I put it in?
我要進去囉
Please.
拜託了
Ouch!
好痛！
Are you okay?
你還好嗎？
Saeki!
佐伯！
What happened? Why are you leaving?
怎麼了？為什麼要回去？
I can't do it with you.
我沒辦法跟你做
I'm sorry.
抱歉
It won't ever happen for me, will it?
果然和我一輩子無緣吧？
-There you are, Kosaka. -Good morning.
-香坂，你在這裡啊 -早安
Good morning. Thank you for staying late yesterday.
早安，謝謝你昨天加班幫我
No problem.
不會
This is for you.
這個給你
My husband went on a business trip to Okinawa.
我老公昨天從沖繩出差回來
It's a souvenir from there.
這是那邊的伴手禮
Chin… suko?
金…楚糕？
CHINSUKO
（金楚糕）
Since when did my urges get so strong that I get worked up over biscuits?
竟然對沖繩特產有感覺 我的性慾到底有多強烈啊？
Are you okay?
你沒事吧？
Oh… Yes.
啊…沒事
Don't tell me…
該不會是…
-Love troubles? -Huh?
-在煩惱戀愛吧？ -什麼？
I was like that too when I was single. I had nothing but love on my mind.
我單身的時候也是這樣 滿腦子都是戀愛
No, it's nothing like that.
不，不是那樣的
Listen, Kosaka.
不過，我說香坂
The more pillars, the better, okay?
支柱越多根越好喔
Pillars?
支柱？
Yes.
對
You know, the ones that hold houses up.
支撐家庭之類的支柱
For me…
對我來說…
I have one for my family, my work and my hobbies.
我有家庭、工作和嗜好
My hobby is creating mangas with my friends.
我的興趣是和朋友製作漫畫
Those three are what hold me up.
這三個支柱支持著我
If I was left with only one…
如果只剩下一根…
Oh.
喔
If you focus too much on one thing then the balance gets thrown off.
如果過度重視一件事，就會失去平衡
I see.
原來如此
Have these, okay?
記得吃喔
Thank you.
謝謝
Pillars, huh?
支柱啊
Hello? Miu?
喂？美雨？
Sorry to call you so early.
不好意思這麼早打給你
You said your daughter spilled juice on the work?
你說你女兒把果汁撒在作品上了？
She did.
對啊
So could we push the deadline a bit?
所以能延後一下交期嗎？
We'll publish someone else's work this time around.
那我們這次就出其他人的作品喔
Huh?
什麼？
You're a mom, so don't overwork yourself. Let's try again next time.
你是媽媽，別太勉強自己了 下次再多指教囉
Yeah.
好
Thanks.
謝謝
A bar by the station?
車站前的酒吧？
Everything is half price because of their anniversary.
對，週年慶全部半價
I have three of these, should we go together?
我有三張，要不要一起去？
I was thinking about going.
我有興趣
How about you, Somei?
染井你呢？
I want to go, but I have to pick up my daughter.
我是想去，但我得去接女兒
Right, of course.
是喔，說的也是
Sorry.
抱歉
Don't apologize.
不會啦
How about lunch, then?
那午餐去怎麼樣？
You think it'll be open?
它白天有開嗎？
-Let's look it up. -Okay.
-我查查看 -好
What do you think?
你覺得如何？
Which one?
哪一個？
I can't do it with you.
我沒辦法跟你做
I'm sorry.
抱歉
Kagiya…
鍵谷…
Good work.
呃…辛苦了
Is it broken?
它壞了嗎？
No, just regular maintenance.
沒有，定期維修而已
Oh.
喔
Um…
那個…
I'm sorry you had to see that the other day.
抱歉，之前讓你看到奇怪的事情
See what?
奇怪的事情？
Last Friday.
上星期五
Uh…
呃…
That's not what you wanted to talk about?
你不是要說這件事嗎？
Uh, no.
呃，不是
They asked me to restock the toner supply, but the person in charge has gone out.
他們說要補碳粉庫存 但負責的人外出了
Could you let me into the storage room?
你能幫我開倉庫嗎？
Oh.
這樣啊
He probably never spared it a second thought.
他完全不在意我的事情嘛
The other day…
之前的事情是…
-Your boyfriend-- -He isn't my boyfriend.
-你男朋友… -他不是我男友
We went to the same school.
只是以前的同學而已
Oh. I see.
啊，是這樣啊
I'll take you to the storage room.
我帶你去倉庫吧
The embarrassment might just kill me.
太尷尬了，好想死
It's the shelf in the back.
在裡面的架子上
Huh?
咦？
It's fine.
沒關係
That's Pac-Man, right?
這是《小精靈》吧？
Huh?
什麼？
Oh. Yeah.
喔，對
My dad loved it, so I used to play a lot as a kid.
小時候我爸很喜歡，所以我很常玩
Same!
我也…
Uh, me too.
呃，我也是
It's so hard getting the fruits.
要吃到水果很難吧？
I can't get past level eight.
我只能過到第八關
I got to 21.
我可以過到21關
Wow, really?
哇，好厲害
How did you do it?
你是怎麼辦到的？
Each ghost has its own territory and moves in a specific pattern.
每個幽靈有自己的範圍 也有特定的移動模式
Kagiya. You really know your stuff.
鍵谷你很懂得很多呢
I suppose.
還好
Thank goodness.
太好了
What?
什麼？
I embarrassed myself earlier, so…
我剛剛好像說了些尷尬的話…
I also never expected it to turn into a talk about video games.
我也沒想到會在這裡聊起遊戲
Oh.
啊
What?
怎麼了？
I need to hand in the papers I printed before the meeting starts.
我得在會議開始前 把印好的資料送過去
I can take care of the rest here, so go ahead.
接下來我可以自己處理，你先走吧
-Sorry. Thank you. -Sure.
-不好意思，麻煩你了 -好的
I don't know exactly why,
雖然不太懂為什麼
but that was fun.
但覺得好開心
KITSUNE 10TH ANNIVERSARY
（狐酒吧十週年紀念）
I'm sharing the photos from the art sphere this weekend.
我來分享這週末藝術領域的照片了
Good job everyone.
大家辛苦了
I said no so many times that I don't even get invited anymore.
我拒絕了很多次 然後就再也沒有收到邀請了
It was so easy when I was just on my own.
單身的時候自在多了呢
I could go wherever I wanted, whenever I wanted.
什麼時候想去哪玩就去哪玩
Eat whatever I wanted.
想吃什麼就吃什麼
Sleep whenever I wanted.
想睡就睡
And draw whenever I felt like it.
興致來時就畫漫畫
RINTARO KIYOKAWA TALKSHOW
（清川隣太郎訪談）
Rintaro Kiyokawa…
清川隣太郎…
Oh, you draw digitally, Kiyokawa?
清川你是用數位作畫喔？
That's amazing.
好厲害
I've never drawn by hand.
我從來沒用手繪畫過
Teach me how to do it sometime.
下次教我怎麼用電腦畫吧？
Sure thing.
好啊
Do you want to try?
你要試試看嗎？
-Right now? -Yeah.
-現在？ -對啊
He was my boyfriend in college.
清川是我大學時的男朋友
Here.
這邊
-This one? -Yeah.
-這個？ -對
I'm sure you'll become a best-selling manga artist one day.
你一定會成為暢銷漫畫家的
Thank you.
謝謝
Good luck with your job hunting, Nana.
你找工作也加油吧，菜菜
Thanks.
好
Well then.
再見
He wanted to chase his dreams.
他想要追尋夢想
I wanted a family and security.
我想要成家和穩定的生活
So we walked down different paths.
我們選擇了不同的道路
RINTARO KIYOKAWA TALKSHOW
（清川隣太郎訪談）
He really did end up becoming an artist.
他真的當上漫畫家了
Is he making a proper living off of it?
他有好好吃飯嗎？
RINTARO KIYOKAWA
（清川隣太郎）
I'm home.
我回來了
Welcome home. You're late today.
歡迎回來，今天真晚呢
I suddenly had to work overtime.
突然被留下來加班
I'm exhausted.
累死了
What's that?
這是什麼？
It's a place close to the company.
公司附近的店家
They asked me to come drink on Friday, but I said no.
同事邀我星期五去喝酒，但我拒絕了
You should go.
你就去嘛
Huh?
什麼？
On Friday I just have to stay for a meeting that ends at five.
星期五的會議 五點結束後我就能離開了
I'll pick up Hina.
我去接日奈吧
Really?
可以嗎？
Thank you, Hide.
謝謝你，阿秀
Kosaka.
香坂
Where is the data from the last interview?
上次取材的資料在哪裡？
One second.
等一下喔
I booked us a table for six o'clock today.
兩位，我訂了今晚六點的位置
Thank you.
謝謝你
It's been ages since the three of us went drinking.
好久沒有三個人一起喝了
We used to go often before Somei's maternity leave.
染井請產假前我們很常去呢
We should thank your husband.
得謝謝你老公才行
Okay.
好
Let's all work hard so we don't have to stay longer.
我們快努力工作不要加班吧
DAYCARE
（托兒所）
You've got to be kidding…
不會吧？
Hello.
喂
Okay.
我知道了
I'll come now.
我現在過去
Hidenao said he's in a meeting until five…
秀直說他要開會到五點…
What is it?
怎麼了嗎？
I'm sorry.
抱歉
I have to go pick her up at daycare.
我必須去托兒所接她
What?
什麼？
She has a fever again.
她又發燒了嗎？
I'm really sorry.
真的很不好意思
Don't be.
不會
Don't worry about us.
不用擔心我們啦
It's tough being a mom.
當媽媽真辛苦呢
You already made the booking, so you guys go have fun, okay?
難得都訂位了 你們兩個就開心地去喝吧
I GAVE HER SOME MEDICINE THE FEVER WENT DOWN, SO DON'T WORRY
（剛剛她吃藥後睡著了 已經退燒了，別擔心）
You're a mom, so don't overwork yourself.
你是媽媽，別太勉強自己了
It's tough being a mom.
當媽媽真辛苦呢
Why does everyone only see me as a mother?
為什麼大家 都只看到身為人母的我呢？
I'm a manga artist, and an office worker.
我有在畫漫畫，也是公司職員
I just happen to be a mom on top of that.
只是再加上母親的身分而已
Cheers!
乾杯！
Here's your pasta.
幫你們上義大利麵
Oh, it looks amazing.
喔，看起來好好吃
It's so good. We have to bring Somei here sometime.
好好吃，下次再帶染井來吧
Right.
好
Thank goodness.
太好了
Huh?
怎麼了？
I thought you maybe wouldn't come.
我以為你不會來呢
Why?
為什麼？
You don't seem to be very fond of getting drinks just the two of us.
你好像不太喜歡單獨兩個人喝酒
That's not true.
沒有這回事
I suppose it's true that I've rarely gone drinking alone with a guy before.
我好像真的不常單獨和男生一起喝酒
Let's share this.
來分這個吧
Okay.
好
Now that he said it, I'm suddenly self-conscious about it.
他這樣說之後，我才突然意識到
No way.
這可不行
He has a girlfriend.
他有女朋友了
-Here you go. -Thanks.
-給你 -謝謝
Is your girlfriend okay with you coming home this late?
你今天晚歸，女朋友沒關係嗎？
Oh.
喔
You've been together five years, was it? That's so long.
你們交往五年了吧？好久呢
Are you considering marriage?
有考慮要結婚了嗎？
I guess.
呃，這個嘛
Hara has two pillars. Work and a girlfriend.
阿原有工作和女友兩根支柱呢
I'm jealous.
真羨慕
I broke up with her.
我跟她分手了
Huh?
什麼？
I'M GLAD HER FEVER IS DOWN
（退燒真是太好了）
SOMETHING HAPPENED SO I CAN'T LEAVE YET I'M SORRY!
（出了點狀況 我還不能回家，對不起）
SORRY
（對不起）
You wouldn't have been able to pick up Hina after all.
結果你還是沒辦法接日奈嘛
I'M FINE
（我這邊沒問題）
KIYOKAWA
（清川）
KEEP IT UP
（別在意）
KIYOKAWA RINTARO
（清川隣太郎）
RINTARO KIYOKAWA #GOLDISMINEONGOINGSERIES
（清川隣太郎 《黃金是我的》連載中）
AMAZING! I WAS EXCITED FOR THE NEW SERIES LOOKING FORWARD TO MORE GORGEOUS DRAWINGS
（好棒喔，好期待新連載 單行本一出我馬上就買）
I'M A HUGE FAN! CAN'T WAIT FOR THE NEW SERIES
（我是大粉絲，期待新作品）
Amazing…
好厲害
Kiyokawa really made his dream come true.
清川真的讓夢想成真了
All I'm doing is causing trouble for everyone.
我卻一直在給別人添麻煩
Everything I do is half-baked.
什麼都做不好
It wasn't supposed to be this way.
不應該是這樣子的
I really loved her. I wanted to be with her forever.
我真的很喜歡她 也想和她一直在一起
Is that why you asked us to come today?
難道是因為這樣 所以今天才邀我們出來嗎？
I didn't want to be alone.
我不想一個人獨處
I can't stop thinking even at work.
就算在工作時也想個不停
I'm past 30, but what am I doing with my life?
有種都過了三十歲 我卻在幹什麼的感覺
Maybe that girlfriend was his only pillar.
也許女朋友是他唯一的支柱
But then…
如果是這樣…
If he lost the only pillar he had…
如果他失去了唯一的柱子…
Are you okay to stay longer, Kosaka?
香坂，時間沒關係嗎？
Yeah, I'm fine.
嗯，沒關係
Want to go somewhere a bit more quiet?
那要去安靜一點的地方嗎？
What?
什麼？
I want to go somewhere private.
我想要去能兩人獨處的地方
Wait, does that mean…?
等等，這意思是？
Excuse me. Can we have the bill?
不好意思，請幫我們結帳
Will Hara and I…
難道我會跟阿原…
Is it okay to make a mistake with me?
即使跟我發生什麼也沒關係？
The gap keeps getting wider…
差距越來越大了
If you're no help, then just quit already.
派不上用場，不如早早辭職算了
I said it's nothing!
我就說沒什麼了！
There's a retro game-café I frequent close to here.
這附近有一間 我常去的復古遊戲喫茶店
Could this be leading to…?
這個發展該不會…